# Victor Trappler

# PhD Student in the AIRSEA team

#### Research interests

I am currently a PhD student of Grenoble-Alpes University in the AIRSEA team (Inria), under the supervision of Arthur Vidard, Élise Arnaud, and Laurent Debreu. My research interests revolve mainly around **Uncertainty Quantification**, and **Inverse Problems**. More specifically, I am interested in Robust Optimization and Optimization under Uncertainties (OUU), in the context of the **estimation of parameters under uncertainties**.

# Education

#### 017 C . DID C.

2017-Current **PhD Student**, AIRSEA, Inria/LJK, Grenoble, France.

Title: Parameter control in the presence of uncertainties

Abstract: Classical methods of parameter estimation usually imply the minimisation of an objective function, that overlooks the role of uncertain parameters. Strategies taking into account these uncertainties need to be defined

 $\textit{Keywords}: \ \mathsf{Parameter} \ \underline{\mathsf{Estimation}}; \ \mathsf{Optimisation} \ \mathsf{under} \ \mathsf{Uncertainties}; \ \mathsf{Data} \ \mathsf{Assimilation}$ 

Advisors: A. Vidard, É. Arnaud, L. Debreu

2015–2017 **MSc Mathematical Modelling and Computation**, *Danmarks Tekniske Universitet*, Kgs. Lyngby, Denmark.

Focus points: Applied mathematical analysis, Dynamical Systems, Scientific Computing, Statistical modelling, Stochastic simulations

2013–2017 **Engineering Degree**, *École Centrale Lyon*, Écully, Interests and courses oriented toward applied mathematics.

## Experience

Internships/Master thesis

2017 Master Thesis, AIRSEA, Inria/LJK, Grenoble, France.

Title: Parameter control in the presence of uncertainties: Robust estimation of bottom friction Advisors: Uffe Høgsbro Thygesen (DTU), Élise Arnaud, Arthur Vidard, Laurent Debreu (Inria)

2015 Intern, EDF R&D, Chatou, France.

Developement of MATLAB tools for hydrodynamical model TELEMAC3D, with the purpose of estimating the residence time

Teaching experience

2017–2019 **Teaching assistant**, *Grenoble-Alpes University*.

Lectures in calculus, algebra, and computer lab sessions in statistics for undergraduates students. Teaching time adding up to *138h*:

o L2 STA301: 90h of lab work on statistics using the R language

o L1 MIASHS: 20h of exercise sessions on calculus

o L1 MAT104: 28h of lectures and exercise sessions on geometry and algebra

2017–2020 Research and Teaching Label, Grenoble-Alpes University.

Specific doctoral training for students wanting to pursue an academic career, mostly on specific teaching methods and reflexions on higher education

7 rue Louis Le Cardonnel – 38100 Grenoble, France

 $\square$  (+33) 6 45 75 14 68 •  $\square$  victor.trappler@univ-grenoble-alpes.fr

**②** team.inria.fr/airsea/en/victor-trappler/ **● ②** vtrappler.github.io

### **Publications**

Victor Trappler, Élise Arnaud, Arthur Vidard, and Laurent Debreu. Robust calibration of numerical models based on relative regret. *Journal of Computational Physics*, page 109952, November 2020.

# Oral and poster presentations

- 2020 Oral presentation at the annual GdR MASCOTNUM PhD meeting (postponed from march 2020), Grenoble, France
- 2019 Oral Presentation at the Applied Inverse Problems Conference, in the mini-symposium "Dimension reduction in inverse problems", Grenoble, France
- 2018 Oral Presentation at the National Colloquium for Data Assimilation, Rennes, France
- 2018 Poster at the Workshop on Sensitivity Analysis and Data Assimilation in Meteorology and Oceanography, Aveiro, Portugal

#### Relevant skills

Languages French (Fluent)

Native

English (Fluent) TOEFL IBT score: 105/120 (2015)

German (Intermediate) Adapted for casual conversations

Sci. Comp. Python 2.7, 3.5+ Advanced: numpy, scipy, scikitlearn & custom packages

R Intermediate
Matlab Intermediate

FORTRAN Basic

C++

Utilitaries LATEX

bash

git

#### Miscellaneous

2020 Representative of non-permanent employees, LJK, Grenoble.

Elected as a representative of the non-permanent employees (PhD, interns, postdocs fellows, engineers) of the Jean Kuntzmann Laboratory. Participation at the lab council